# Gerry Wood

Sr. Software Engineer | Mobile Architect



#### About me

I have 20+ years of advanced software development experience with firms such as Bank of America, Merrill Lynch, US Trust, Fleet as well as numerous service providers within the financial services sector. I am a Senior Engineer with over 7 years of experience building iOS mobile applications and have led development for major mobile initiatives. My specialty is highly scalable and deeply connected applications for both large and small implementations. I am a proponent of well-crafted code and elegant designs. I believe engineers are artists and their code is a canvas. Code should read like a well written passage.

### Contact -

- gerald.wood@lknlife.com
- in geraldewood
- 704.453.3237
- cyberclectic
- 2638 Lee Lawing Rd.
- brevityisgolden
- Lincolnton, NC 28092
- # Iknlife.com

#### Languages -

- 📤 English Native Language
- Spanish Basic Knowledge

#### **Education**

Bachelor of Science | Business Administration

Management Information Systems and Finance

Edwardsville, IL

#### Professional Skills —

Leadership Active Listening Collaboration Flexibility Autonomy Eye for Details Mentoring Forward Thinking

#### Other Interests

- Volunteering
- Travel +
- Learning
- Family
- Music
- Fishing

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### 2022-Today

#### Sr. Software Engineer | Mobile Architect SumUp

Remote

- Development of key mobile initiatives including Global Loyalty, Mobile Check Deposit, Wires, Check Issuance and Statements.
- Helped grow user base by 40% in last quarter of 2022.
- Focused on iOS development using Swift with MVVM and Protocol Oriented Programming best practices.
- DevOps tasks using GitHub Actions, GitHub Pages, Microsoft App Center and Apple App Store Connect integration(s).

#### 2017-2021

#### Sr. Mobile Engineer | Architect Bank of America (Retired)

Charlotte, NC

- Delivered key mobile initiatives for Bank of America flagship mobile application (iOS, Android). Development support and delivery for other mobile applications including MyMerrill, MerrillEdge, BofA Health, etc.
- Refactored codebase into distributable frameworks using xcframeworks and Swift Package Manager (SPM).
- Lead iOS Engineer on Life Plan, which delivered over \$1b in added deposits and organic growth within consumer bank in first year. Leveraged SpriteKit and other advanced UI designs to create an immersive user experience.
- Helped grow Erica (Virtual Financial Assistant) use to over 1 billion interactions.
- Facilitated Zelle growth to almost 20 million users.

#### 2001-2017

#### Various Engineering and Team Lead Roles Bank of America

- Responsible for development, team management and project coordination for numerous web and client server based applications.
- Included customer facing applications such as bankofamerica.com and the treasury services portal.

## </> Technology DNA

